<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nabin Acharya</title><link>https://nacharya.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Nabin Acharya</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 14:37:03 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nacharya.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Generics in the Go Language</title><link>https://nacharya.github.io/posts/genericsgo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 14:37:03 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nacharya.github.io/posts/genericsgo/</guid><description>Generics in Go Some well known documents from the past
Type parameters proposal
Why Generics?
The Next Steps
It is December 2021 and &amp;hellip;.we have Go 1.18 beta 1 available. The Golang team is hard at work on Golang 1.18, which will be released in February 2022, and it looks like it’s going to be a big one.
Once upon a time in C++, when templates were introduced, lots of templates with amazing capabilities came into light, then came STL and standardized most of it to make things extremely powerful and usable.</description></item><item><title>Articles</title><link>https://nacharya.github.io/articles/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 11:01:12 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nacharya.github.io/articles/</guid><description>Articles Coming Soon !</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://nacharya.github.io/projects/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 10:57:49 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nacharya.github.io/projects/</guid><description>Service : Empowering students with Technology Eblackboard This project was all about creating a small educational platform for people in need of such. Created small lab environments using Raspberry Pi.
Creative Curiosity: Code Play Languages: Go, Python3, TypeScript, C, C++, F# Frameworks: NodeJS, TensorFlow, Jupyter, Hugo UI: React, Angular S3 Data Access: edge_access Mostly code playground for the Tech surrounding 2022</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://nacharya.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 18:19:10 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nacharya.github.io/about/</guid><description>Data, Processing and Learning Lots of data is easy to collect. It has to be persisted somewhere. Data has to be processed to find out what is relevant. If irrelevant data is thrown away, it reduces your cost to store it, reduces the cost to mine it. Data come it many many different formats and in many different channels in the Cloud. Continuous growth of information makes things interesting and it does make you look at Technology in different curious ways.</description></item><item><title>Data Analytics Links</title><link>https://nacharya.github.io/posts/data-analytics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 15:30:09 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nacharya.github.io/posts/data-analytics/</guid><description>Some of the most useful courses online The Data Science Course 2021: Complete Data Science Bootcamp. The course is very precise and well organized. They have a good combination of theory with good practical examples tht are relevent today
Principles, Statistical and Computational Tools for Reproducible Data Science Harvard also has a very nice Master&amp;rsquo;s program in Data Science
Berkeley Online Data Analytics Boot Camp : Berkeley also has a one year Master&amp;rsquo;s program on Analytics and Data Science.</description></item><item><title>Python 3.10</title><link>https://nacharya.github.io/posts/p310/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 14:21:32 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nacharya.github.io/posts/p310/</guid><description>Python 3.10 is here Python 3.10 is now released. It has a few features worth talking about. Some of these features never existed before in Python (surprisingly!)
Structural Mattern Matching In the traditional programming languages, this is usually referred to as the switch ...case statements. Although syntactically it looks like a switch ... case statement, it is a lot more than that.
It allows you to detect and deconstruct different structures the data is defined as, and lets you use patterns of your definition.</description></item><item><title>WSLv2 and Windows 10 Pro</title><link>https://nacharya.github.io/posts/wsl/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nacharya.github.io/posts/wsl/</guid><description>Installing WSLv2 on Windows and using Linux natively on Windows Pre-requisites Windows 10 May 2020 (2004) or Windows 10 May 2019 (1903) or Windows 10 November 2019 (1909) or later Computer with Hyper-V support for virtualization Pathces : If you have Windows revisions 1903 or 1909 make sure you can install the patches: Windows Update KB4566116
1. WSL has to be enabled Once the installation is complete, please enable the WSL using the following Powershell</description></item><item><title>Markdown Syntax Guide for writing markdown content</title><link>https://nacharya.github.io/posts/markdown-syntax/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nacharya.github.io/posts/markdown-syntax/</guid><description>&lt;p>This article offers a sample of basic Markdown syntax that can be used in Hugo content files, also it shows whether basic HTML elements are decorated with CSS in a Hugo theme.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rich Content within Markdown using Hugo shortcodes</title><link>https://nacharya.github.io/posts/rich-content/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nacharya.github.io/posts/rich-content/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hugo ships with several &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/content-management/shortcodes/#use-hugos-built-in-shortcodes">Built-in Shortcodes&lt;/a> for rich content, along with a &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/about/hugo-and-gdpr/">Privacy Config&lt;/a> and a set of Simple Shortcodes that enable static and no-JS versions of various social media embeds.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Placeholder Text</title><link>https://nacharya.github.io/posts/placeholder-text/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nacharya.github.io/posts/placeholder-text/</guid><description>&lt;p>Lorem est tota propiore conpellat pectoribus de pectora summo.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Math Typesetting for Math Equations in Markdown</title><link>https://nacharya.github.io/posts/math-typesetting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nacharya.github.io/posts/math-typesetting/</guid><description>&lt;p>Mathematical notation in a Hugo project can be enabled by using third party JavaScript libraries.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Emoji Support using Hugo shortcodes</title><link>https://nacharya.github.io/posts/emoji-support/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nacharya.github.io/posts/emoji-support/</guid><description>&lt;p>Emoji can be enabled in a Hugo project in a number of ways.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>