<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on N Acharya</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on N Acharya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 11:50:56 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>LLM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/llm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 11:50:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/llm/</guid>
      
      <description>Scope Given there is so much information available in the Internet on Generative AI, let&amp;rsquo;s keep this brief and to the point of relevant topics.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start by asking ChatGPT ChatGPT : What is Large Language Model ?
A large language model, often referred to simply as an &amp;ldquo;LLM,&amp;rdquo; is a type of artificial intelligence (AI) model designed to understand and generate human language&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;.
Here are the main points that ChatGPT came with &amp;hellip;.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go: Contexts, Channels &amp; Goroutines</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gocontext/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 14:36:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gocontext/</guid>
      
      <description>Go: Contexts, Channels &amp;amp; Goroutines Concurrency In Computer Science Concurrency is very important because efficient resource management of core resources like Processor, Memory and Network usage. Any large complex probelem can be broken down into smaller problem tasks that can be handled concurrently. This also allows applications to be faster and scale efficiently.
When tasks can be broken down into smaller tasks, responsiveness of systems can be enhanced and also create better human interactiveness.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI AI AI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ai-init/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 23:24:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ai-init/</guid>
      
      <description>AI, AI, AI &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;.. the many different areas &amp;hellip;. and growing! One of the key achievements of AI is the rise of Human Productivity. One of the best toolset mankind can use to improve human civilization.
Given the numbers of AI publications has increased from 162,444 in 2010 to 334,497 in 2021, this is a fast moving disruptive field of Technology with rapid acceleration. It is very difficult to stay on top of the latest research in this field.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generics in the Go Language</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/genericsgo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 14:37:03 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/genericsgo/</guid>
      
      <description>Generics in Go Some well known documents from the past
Type parameters proposal
Why Generics?
The Next Steps
It is December 2021 and &amp;hellip;.we have Go 1.18 beta 1 available. The Golang team is hard at work on Golang 1.18, which will be released in February 2022, and it looks like it’s going to be a big one.
Once upon a time in C++, when templates were introduced, lots of templates with amazing capabilities came into light, then came STL and standardized most of it to make things extremely powerful and usable.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Analytics Links</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/data-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 15:30:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/data-analytics/</guid>
      
      <description>Some of the most useful courses online The Data Science Course 2021: Complete Data Science Bootcamp. The course is very precise and well organized. They have a good combination of theory with good practical examples tht are relevent today
Principles, Statistical and Computational Tools for Reproducible Data Science Harvard also has a very nice Master&amp;rsquo;s program in Data Science
Berkeley Online Data Analytics Boot Camp : Berkeley also has a one year Master&amp;rsquo;s program on Analytics and Data Science.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python 3.10</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/p310/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 14:21:32 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/p310/</guid>
      
      <description>Python 3.10 is here Python 3.10 is now released. It has a few features worth talking about. Some of these features never existed before in Python (surprisingly!)
Structural Mattern Matching In the traditional programming languages, this is usually referred to as the switch ...case statements. Although syntactically it looks like a switch ... case statement, it is a lot more than that.
It allows you to detect and deconstruct different structures the data is defined as, and lets you use patterns of your definition.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WSLv2 and Windows 10 Pro</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/wsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/wsl/</guid>
      
      <description>Installing WSLv2 on Windows and using Linux natively on Windows Pre-requisites Windows 10 May 2020 (2004) or Windows 10 May 2019 (1903) or Windows 10 November 2019 (1909) or later Computer with Hyper-V support for virtualization Pathces : If you have Windows revisions 1903 or 1909 make sure you can install the patches: Windows Update KB4566116
1. WSL has to be enabled Once the installation is complete, please enable the WSL using the following Powershell</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown Syntax Guide for writing markdown content</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/markdown-syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/markdown-syntax/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article offers a sample of basic Markdown syntax that can be used in Hugo content files, also it shows whether basic HTML elements are decorated with CSS in a Hugo theme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rich Content within Markdown using Hugo shortcodes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rich-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rich-content/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hugo ships with several &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/shortcodes/#use-hugos-built-in-shortcodes&#34;&gt;Built-in Shortcodes&lt;/a&gt; for rich content, along with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/about/hugo-and-gdpr/&#34;&gt;Privacy Config&lt;/a&gt; and a set of Simple Shortcodes that enable static and no-JS versions of various social media embeds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Placeholder Text</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/placeholder-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/placeholder-text/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lorem est tota propiore conpellat pectoribus de pectora summo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math Typesetting for Math Equations in Markdown</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/math-typesetting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/math-typesetting/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mathematical notation in a Hugo project can be enabled by using third party JavaScript libraries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emoji Support using Hugo shortcodes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/emoji-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/emoji-support/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Emoji can be enabled in a Hugo project in a number of ways.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
