<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on N Acharya</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on N Acharya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 10:22:22 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 Software Architectural Patterns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/top5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 10:22:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/top5/</guid>
      
      <description>Top 5 Software Architectural patterns Software Architectures are the foundations to Software systems. Choice and correct use of an appropriate pattern is really important when building large software systems
1. Layered Architecture A system is separated into sub-systems as distictictly different layers that communicates to each other layer it is adjacent to.
A very common example of Architecture is the following list of layers
Presentation Layer Business Layer Persistence Layer Database Layer A very widely used pattern that includes UI patterns like MVP as it allows for the separation of Data Layer, Business Logic layer and User Presentation (UI) layers Each layer having a distinct responsibility makes it so the changes in one layer will only impact the adjacent layer and not all the components of the system</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spirit Mind Body</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/spirit-mind-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 16:46:13 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/spirit-mind-body/</guid>
      
      <description>Spirit Humans need spirit well above their mind and body. Some people call it Religion, some call it the Universal Truth. It is very difficult to describe logically, but it exists &amp;ndash; in spirit
Have been involved with multiple religious faiths, atheistic beliefs, rational scientific explanations &amp;ndash; and &amp;ndash; realized that there is this notion of spirit that every human needs
It is something up there somewhere that can only be imagined for truthfulness beyond everything</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architecture: What is it ? why do we care ?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 16:48:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/architecture/</guid>
      
      <description>Architecture So what is Architecture ? As a kid , I only saw that everyone ties in the word Architecture to Buildings and Physical Structures that somehow captures human emotions intellectually.
Folks working in Technology were a few and the word Architect was hardly used to describe anyone in the Software/IT profession.
People in the Software world have long argued the use of the word Architecture. Here are some assumptions on the definition of the word Architecture</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Three Pillars: Foundational Belief</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the_three_pillars/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 13:49:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the_three_pillars/</guid>
      
      <description>The Three Pillars: Foundational Belief Having spent many years working in the IT industry, here are some foundational pillars that have helped me all along. The industry is ever evolving and always progressing. With the rise of the internet in the &amp;rsquo;90s came the Internet Landslide of information and thus came the challenge of traversing this landslide
Turns out the human mind is capable of so much &amp;hellip; so much more.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
